CURRICULUM VITAE

Mohammed Abdul Ahmed Khan

9 Richens Close, Email:AHD_KHAN413@YAHOO.COM;

Hounslow United Kingdom. Tel No.: 00447772342082

TW3 1PL.

Summary:

A confident and reliable Cloud engineer with extensive practical experience of working with Cloud Network and resolving any support issues that raised. Possessing a proven ability to administer and control the operation, configuration and maintenance of Cloud Network, as well as having an eye for detail and able to multi-task under pressure. An excellent communicator can relate well with people at all levels and has the flexibility of working well as part of a team and on my own. Provides outstanding customer service and a strong ability to communicate technical concepts in a non-technical manner.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

Cloud Platform Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services and Open Stack.

Virtualization VMware Infrastructure 3, vSphere4, vSphere5, VMware View 4.5,

4.6

DevOps Tools Puppet, Chef, Ansible, terraform, Vagrant, Docker Packer and

Kubernetes.

Scripting Languages PERL, Ruby, Python, Shell Programming, Bash Script, Json.

Networking Virtual Network, ExpressRoute, Load Balancer, DNS, VPN

Gateway, Application Gateway

Identity & Access

Azure Active Directory, Azure Identity, Multi-Factor Authentication

Management (MF)

(MFA)

Operating Systems Red Hat 5.x/6.x/7.x, CentOS 5.x/6.x/7.x, Ubuntu, Windows

Servers 2003/2008R2/2012/R2/2016/Datacenter, Windows

7/8/10 & Mac OS X

Security Concepts IDS/IPS, DDoS, Social engineering, ACL, Hashing, Encryption,

Hardening, DRP/BCP, Cryptography & SSL

Backup & Restore Veeam Backup Solutions for vSphere Environments, Commvault,

Azure Recovery Vault.

Database SQL, MYSQL, Enterprise NoSQL, Cassandra.

Web/App Servers Web Logic, Web Sphere, Apache Tomcat, JBOSS

Monitoring Tool SCOM, Dyna Trace, Splunk.

Office and Visual Studio, Git, and Office 365

Developer Services

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Azure Devops Engineer, PwC, London, UK

Feb 2019 - Till Date

- Manage Windows and Linux servers in Azure
- Configure NSG groups in Azure
- Configuring Public and Private Load Balancers in Azure
- Managing Web Application firewalls in Azure
- ARM templates
- Support Azure Infrastructure end to end
- Manage Hybrid cloud
- Configure and manage Azure AD and AD connect
- Configure Azure Policies and Azure security center
- Creating and Adding Azure VMs to availability sets and zones
- Configure Site to Site VPN, Point to Site and ExpressRoute
- Migration of virtual Servers to Azure using Azure Site Recovery
- Configure VM backup using Azure recovery vault services
- Configuring Azure AD and integrate with on-premise Active Directory using Azure AD Connect
- Create and manage Azure SQL databases, WebApps and other PaaS services
- Monitor Azure services using OMS and Application Insights
- Deployment of Load Balancers, Virtual Machines and other resources using ARM, JSON and PowerShell templates

- Configuration and management of Azure Kubernetes Service
- Managing desires state of servers using Ansible and Terraform
- Secure pods using Kubernetes RBAC
- Create and deploy docker images
- GIT integration with Azure and configuration of CI/CD using Azure pipelines
- Good understanding of overall DevOps tools and culture

Azure Cloud Engineer, MITIE

March 2017- Feb 2019

- Working with multiple technical teams, architects, security officers, managers and business users, reviewed and documented workloads, system dependencies and business requirements.
- Manage and maintain Azure EA account.
- Create, manage and maintain Azure subscriptions.
- Manage access for users, groups, service principals, and managed identities using RBAC and the Azure portal.
- Create, adjust and modify ARM templates and Power shell Scripts.
- Azure Storage technologies (Azure SQL, Data Warehouse, Blob, etc)
- Designed and configured Azure Virtual Networks (VNets), subnets, Azure network settings, DHCP address blocks, DNS settings, security policies and routing.
- Deployed Azure IaaS virtual machines (VMs) and Cloud services (PaaS role instances) into secure VNets and subnets.
- Azure Alerts and monitoring configuration.
- Create and configure Runbooks for Auto scheduling and DSC. (Azure Automation)
- Exposed Virtual machines and cloud services in the VNets to the Internet using Azure External Load Balancer, Application Gateway and NVA (Silver peak).
- Provided high availability for laaS VMs and PaaS role instances for access from other services in the VNet.
- Designed Network Security Groups (NSGs) to control inbound and outbound access to network interfaces (NICs), VMs and subnets.

- Setup Azure Virtual Appliances to meet security requirements as software based appliance functions (firewall, WAN optimization and intrusion detections).
- Utilized NSGs for layer 4 Access Control List (ACLs) for incoming and outgoing packets.
- Used firewall appliance where requirements call for layer 7 security models.
- Designed User Defined Routes with custom route tables for specific cases to force tunneling to the Internet via on-premise network and control use of virtual appliances in the customer's Azure environment.
- Managed IP Forwarding for VMs and role instances acting as virtual appliances.

AWS Cloud Engineer, HCL Technology

Feb. 2015 - January 2017

- Built a VPC, established the site-to- site VPN connection between Data Center and AWS.
- Built S3 buckets and managed policies for S3 buckets and used S3 Bucket and
 Glacier for storage and backup on AWS.
- Work with other teams to help develop the **Puppet** infrastructure to conform to various requirements including security and compliance of managed servers.
- Help with the creation of dev standards for Puppet module development including best practices for version control (git).
- Designing and implementing fully automated server build management, monitoring and deployment by using Technologies like **Puppet**.
- Perform troubleshooting and monitoring of the Linux server on AWS using Zabbix , Nagios and Splunk .
- Management and Administration of AWS
 Services CLI, EC2, VPC, S3, ELB Glacier, Route 53, Cloudtrail, IAM, and
 Trusted Advisor services.
- Created automated pipelines in AWS CodePipeline to deploy Docker containers in AWS ECS using services like CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, S3 and puppet.
- Worked on JIRA for defect/issues logging & tracking and documented all my work using CONFLUENCE.
- Integrated services like GitHub, AWS CodePipeline, Jenkins and AWS Elastic Beanstalk to create a deployment pipeline.

- Good Experience in architecting and configuring secure cloud VPC using private and public networks through subnets in AWS.
- Amazon IAM service enabled to grant permissions and resources to users. Managed roles and permissions of users with the help of AWS IAM.
- Develop push-button automation for app teams for deployments in multiple environments like Dev, QA, and Production.
- Initiating alarms in CloudWatch service for monitoring the server's performance, CPU
 Utilization, disk usage etc. to take recommended actions for better performance.
- Configured AWS Multi Factor Authentication in IAM to implement 2-step authentication of user's access using Google Authenticator and AWS Virtual MFA.
- Included security groups, network ACLs, Internet Gateways, and Elastic IP's to ensure a safe area for organization in AWS public cloud.
- Writing UNIX shell scripts to automate the jobs and scheduling cron jobs for job automation using commands with Crontab.
- Wrote Ansible Playbooks with PythonSSH as the Wrapper to Manage Configurations of AWS Nodes and Test Playbooks on AWS instances using Python .Experience with Puppet to more easily manage enterprise Puppet deployments
- Design AWS Cloud Formation templates to create custom sized VPC, subnets,
 NAT to ensure successful deployment of Web applications and database templates
- Created scripts in Python, which integrated with Amazon API to control instance operations.
- Coordinate/assist developers with establishing and applying appropriate branching, labelling /naming conventions using GIT source control.

Systems/Network Engineer, HCL Technology Jul. 2012 – Feb. 2015.

- Completed Hardware and Software builds for new server deployments, ensuring adherence to documented build procedures.
- Installed and maintained RJ45, CAT6 and/or optical fiber cables across the Data Center and various MDFs around the lot.
- Installed and maintained AC/DC power PDU's (Sentry- Server Tech) with Temperature &Humidity sensors, connections Master/Slave, configuring all the PDU's in the Sentry Management application.
- Assisted in the operation, and maintenance of electrical, mechanical, and HVAC equipment within the Data Center/Facility.

- Facilitated the growth of the IT Infrastructure Service support and participated in the development of its products and services.
- Audited changes for IP's, Gateway, ports, etc.
- Installed and administered UNIX, RedHat Linux and Windows NT servers.
- Install and Configure Linux with Apache, Oracle 8I and PHP (LAMP Project).

Infrastructure Engineer, Equal Solutions Ltd.

July. 2011 - Jun. 2012

- Migration of SCCM 2012 to 2016 (1610, 1703 ver) CB (CAS-1, Primary Site 12, Secondary - 25 & DP - 45 with 100000 Clients & 4000 Servers)
- Deployment of Office 365 pro plus for 60000 Users
- Migration of Windows 7, 8.1 on windows 10 OS.
- Windows In-tune integration with SCCM.
- Design documents.
- Solution design & implementation of SCCM infra for Operating system deployment.
- (OSD), Patching\Hardware & Software inventory \Software distribution \ License Management etc.
- Mac OS Management solution using JAMF Casper.
- Deployment of CSI tool with integration of SCCM 2012 for Third -Party Patch management.
- Technical SOPs & documents.
- Technical Lead for SCCM team.
- Vendor Management.

EDUCATIONAL PROFILE:

Qualifications	Name of the Institution	Board/ University	Year of Passing
Msc in Mobile Communications	University Of East London	University Of East London(U.K)	June2011
B.Tech	Royal Institute Of Science And Technology	Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (India)	June 2008
Intermediate	St.Mary's Junior Collage		Mar -2004

		Board Of Intermediate	
		Education(India)	
SSC	Roch Memorial High School	SSC(India)	Mar-2002

PERSONAL PROFILE:

Gender & Marital Status: Male & Married

Nationality: Indian

COMMUNICATION SKILLS:

Read : English, Hindi and Telugu.

Write : English, Hindi and Telugu.

Speak : English, Hindi, Urdu and Telugu.

References will be provided on request.